John C. Ripplinger

West Valley City, UT 84120 385-370-3136 johnrip89@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-ripplinger-4714315b/

Portfolio: https://johnrip89.github.io/John-s-Portfolio/

GitHub: https://github.com/johnrip89/

SUMMARY

I'm a certified full stack web developer. I have three years of coding experience with HTML, GIT, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, React, Handlebars, Heroku, SQL and MongoDB. I have developed over 25 different websites and applications. I'm a hardworking, self-motivated professional that can adapt and learn quickly.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap, and APIs

PROJECTS

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/johnrip89/Weather-Dashboard | https://johnrip89.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- Summary: A weather application that produces a 5-day forecast for the selected city.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap

SalonMe eCommerce Website | https://github.com/dylanshoemaker/SalonMe | https://salonme.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: An ecommerce website for Salon that has the ability to schedule appointments.
- Role: Front-end and Calendar Creator
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, react-big-calendar, react-big-scheduler, and react-datetime-picker

Who's The Best? | https://github.com/Novavon420/Group-Project-Fantastic-4 | https://novavon420.github.io/Group-Project-Fantastic-4/

- Summary: A website that compares NBA players stats by year/season.
- Role: Co-Author
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API, and Bootstrap

EDUCATION

U of U Trilogy IT Certification — Full Stack Web Development

June 2021 to Nov 2021

Western Governors University — *Bachelor's degree in Database Administration*Jan 2019 to June 2021

DevMountain Certification - Basic Coding - Web Development

April 2021 to May 2021

Utah State University, Logan, Utah — *Bachelor's degree in Marketing*Aug 2011 to May 2014

Salt Lake Community College, SLC, Utah — *Associate's degree in General Education* Aug 2010 to Aug 2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

Enerbank USA, South Salt Lake City, Utah

Senior Customer Relations Coordinator

May 2015 to present

File and investigate customer formal complaints submitted by mail, online, or phone for assigned Program Sponsors. Create effective communication between the bank, homeowner, and contractor to resolve a variety of concerns and issues with the home improvement project that we helped finance. Weekly meetings to report on current complaints with management. Respond to customer credit disputes and requests for validation of debt.

- Consistently meet deadlines and stay on top of projects while working remotely and in the office.
- Frequently resolve difficult complaints where a simple resolution is not common.

Zupas Cafe, Lehi, Utah (AGM) Culinary Manager

May 2014 to March 2015

Delivered exceptional service with a smile. Managed all orders, invoices, inventory, and costs/expenses. Hired, managed, and trained staff. Attended monthly corporate meetings and conducted daily store meetings. Worked 12 hour shifts several times a week and reached overtime every week.

- Avoided customer dissatisfaction by quickly resolving problems and giving great customer service.
- Managed and trained kitchen staff to achieve corporate goals each month.